Benjamin Franklin Papers Part 14 -- Materials held at the University of Pennsylvania 1705-1788 Mss.B.F85inventory14
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence (University of Pennsylvania), 1758-1788
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1784 November 17; A.L.S. 2p.; Perkins, William Lee. Kingston
    Desiring to know if he ever received a letter from him, as well as a paper on Influenza.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1784 November 28; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Adams, John. Auteuil
    Inviting him to dinner.
  - Appendix, 1784 December 3; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Adams, Mrs. John. Auteuil
    Thanking him for the oil. Recommends a sedan chair instead of a carriage.
  - Appendix, 1784 December 17; L. in 3d P. 1p.; Messrs. Jackson, Tracy, Donnaldson and Temple. Paris
    Requesting passports for themselves and their servants.
  - Appendix, 1784 August 19, to December 22; Mem. S. 9p.; Angenend, ------. Paris
    Bills for tailoring.
  - Appendix, 1784; Printed N. 1p.; de Gehag fils, Da Pachelbel
    Announcing the death of the Duke de Deux-Ponts on October 5, 1784.
  - Appendix, 1785 January 27; A.L.S. 4p.; Ourry, Ann. Kinsale
    Asking his help to recover some land in New York, lost in a law-suit by her father.
  - Appendix, 1785 March 23; A.L.S. 2p.; De Bouille, La Marquise. Paris
    Begging his influence on behalf of the unfortunate Mlle. [Ann] Ourry.
  - Appendix, 1785 February and March; Mem. 3p.; Finck, Jacques
    Bill for household expenses.
  - Appendix, 1785 April 5; Diploma S. Huet de Froberville. 1p.; La Société Royale de Physique, d'Histoire Naturelle et des Arts d'Orleans. Orléans
    Certificate of his election as honorary member.
  - Appendix, 1785 April 7; A.L.S. 1p.; Huet de Froberville. Secretaire Perpetuel. Orléans
    Announcing Dr. Franklin's election as Honorary Member of the Société Royale de Physique, d'Histoire Naturelle et des Arts d'Orleans.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1785 May 18; L.S. [Anquetin] De Beaulieu, Premier Surv[eillan]t, et al. 2p.; Amis, La Loge des Bons. Rouen
    Expressing their gratification at his consenting to become a member of their Lodge.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1785 May 18; L. S. Le Bourgeois de Belleville, Sec[retar]y. 4p.; Amis, La Loge des Bons. Rouen
    List of the officers of the Lodge.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1785 May 21; A.L.S. 2p.; Collignon, -----. Dieuze, Lorraine
    Sends him a copy of his book on the clearing of waste lands; desires the other copies forwarded to the United States, for sale.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1785 July 12; A.L.S. 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    His intention to join Dr. Franklin at Cowes, and go with him to America.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1785 July 15; A.L.S. 1p.; Jones, Capt. John Paul. Paris
    Desiring a certificate of the indemnity offered Denmark for certain prizes restored to the British.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1785 July 18; A.L.S. 1p.; Jefferson, Thomas. Paris
    Glad to hear that he has reached Rouen, without being much fatigued; precautions he has taken to protect his baggage. A M. Duplessis wishes a long memoir on some animals of South America copied for Dr. Franklin; does he care to have it?
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1786 December 6; Printed N.S. Colson, Agent. 1p.; La "Maison Philantropique." Paris
    Announcing a meeting of their Society; list of candidates for membership.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1787 September 18; A.L.S. 2p.; Hopkinson, Francis
    Petition against the abolishment of his salary as Judge of Admiralty; begs Dr. Franklin to favor his petition when it comes before the Council.
  - Appendix, A.L.S. 2p.; Bastide, Madame. Passy
    Asking for money.
  - Appendix, April 29; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; M. and Mme. N. Baussan, Paris
    Invitation to dinner on May 6th.
  - Appendix, L. in 3d P. 2p.; Boux, -----
    Concerning money due M. Boux, who entered the United States service with the understanding that his passage money and certain other specified expenses should be paid in addition to his salary.
  - Appendix, A.L. 1p.; -----, -----
    Warning him against two renegade Americans, Jameson, of Charlestown, and Robert Tuitten.
  - Appendix, January 1; A.L.S. 1p.; Cochran, -----
    A New Year's greeting.
  - Appendix, L. in 3d P. 1p.; Noelporion, Madame Marie
    Application for assistance from a poor widow with several children.
  - Appendix, 1p.; -----, -----
    Bill for work done in the wine cellas.
  - 1777 February 2, D.S. B[enjamin] Franklin, Silas Deane and Arthur Lee. 1p.; Messrs. Franklin and Deane
    Resolution concerning the attitude of the United States towards France or Spain, in case either of these nations should conclude a Treaty of Amity and Commerce with the United States, and in consequence enter into a war with Great Britain.
  - 1777 February 2 and 5, D.S. B[enjamin] Franklin, Silas Deane and Arthur Lee. 2p.; Messrs. Franklin and Deane
    Resolved to defend and support the public cause at all hazards and, for such purpose, to pledge their persons or hazard the censure of the Congress by exceeding their instructions, and to cheerfully risk their liberty or life.
  - to ----- Mercier., 1777 June 23; D.S. Silas Deane for the Commissioners. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin. Paris
    Agreement for the repair of arms.
  - to The Council of Massachusetts., 1777 December 21; A. Dr. of L. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin. Paris
    Acknowledging their favor of October 29th with news of Burgoyne's defeat and surrender.
  - to Le Ray de Chaumont., A. Dr. of N. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Arrangement by which he and his grandson had their dinners at M. de Chaumont's house.
  - to Comte de Vergennes?., [1777.]; 1p.; The American Commissioners
    Denying complicity in the conduct of Capt. [Gustavus] Conyngham. Dr. by Ferdinand Grand of L.
  - to [Henry Laurens]., 1778 March 31; L.S. 1P.; Franklin, Benjamin
    Testifying to the worth of Silas Deane and expressing a belief that his recall was due to misrepresentations.
  - to Arthur Lee., 1778 April 6; L.S. 1p.; Appendix. Passy
    Asserting his belief that orders given by any two of the Commissioners are sufficient; reasons why Lee was not consulted in this particular instance.
  - to James Lovell., 1778 July 22; L.S. 1p.; Appendix. Passy
    Glad to learn that Mr. [Silas] Deane is likely to return, with honor, on a mission to Holland.
  - Expense Account., 1778 December 29 to 31; Mem. 1p.; Appendix
  - to [Simeon] Deane., [1778.]; L.S. B[enjamin] F[ranklin], S[ilas] D[eane], A[rthur] L[ee.] 2p.; The American Commissioners
    Explicit instructions covering his secret commission to Congress.
  - Expense Account., 1779 December 7; 1779 February 23; Mem. 14p.; Appendix
    Dr. Franklin's expenses, public and private.
  - to Horneca, Fizeaux and Co., 1779 April 20; Dr. of L.S. 1p.; Appendix. Passy
    An order to replace certain goods sent by mistake from Nantes to the United States; enclosing copy of the invoice.
    (2p. In French.)
  - to Comlesse de Forbach., [1779. June.]; A. Dr. of L. 1p.; Appendix
    Acknowledging her gift of a pair of scissors; constant reminders of her at every turn; she has impressed him as one of the best, wisest and mot amiable of women.
  - to Mrs. [Elizabeth] Partridge, 1779 October 11; A. Dr. of L. 2p.; Appendix. Passy
    An amusing account of French politeness and the agreeable manners of the French ladies. Had print of the Boston newspapers. Sends her his miniature on china.
  - to James Lovell, 1779 October 17; L.S. 1p.; Appendix. Passy
    Has never meddled in the quarrel between [Silas] Deane and [Arthur] Lee; still believes [Silas] Deane to be innocent of embezzlement and peculation.
  - to Whom it May Concern., 1780 March 29; A. Dr. of D. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin
    Certifying to the genuineness of the signatures of Thomas Jefferson and P[atrick] Henry.
  - to Whom it May Concern., 1780 April 14; A. Dr. of D. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin
    Certifying to the genuineness of the signature of Lombart de Laneuville.
  - to Captain Pierre Landais, L'Orient., 1780 June 7; L.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin
    Leaves the propriety of Landais's conduct to other judges; waives any further dispute, but charges him not to meddle with the command of the "Alliance" or to create any disturbance on board of her.
    E. Setting forth Landais's refusal to receive Dr. Franklin's letter. S. James Moylan, 1780, July 7, l'Orient.
  - to ----- -----., [1780.]; L. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Offence given to the French Court by Mr. [John] Adams's letters to the Comte de Vergennes; difficulties due to having more than one Agent at one time in one place; unwise remarks made lately by certain Americans in Paris; believes America would gain by a courteous attitude towards France.
  - to ----- -----., 1780; Printed D. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin
    Form to be issued by Dr. Franklin as a passport to American travellers.
  - Memorandum., [1780.]; A. Mem. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    List of papers relating to the frigate "Alliance."
  - to [Etienne-François,] Marquis de Turgot., 1781 May 1; A. Dr. of L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin
    Technical description of a new stove, accompanied by a diagram.
  - Memorandum., 1781 September 31 and 1782 January 8; Mem. 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    List of Dr. Franklin's books moved from his chambers to his office.
  - to Baron de Thun., 1782 April 24; A.L.S 1p.; Appendix. Passy
    Promising to have arrested on sight any person answering the Baron's description.
  - to Leopold M.A. Caldani, President of the Academy of Sciences, Letters and Arts of Padua., 1782 April 26; A. Dr. of L. 1p.; Appendix. Passy
    Accepting his election as honorary member of the Academy of Sciences, Letters and Arts of Pauda; promising to send them natural history specimens, on his return to America.
  - to Marquis de la Fayette., 1782 September 17; A.L. 2p.; Appendix. Passy
    Pleased to learn that Madame de la Fayette has another daughter; recommends naming his children after the States, beginning with the oldest and running through the thirteen; hopes that such States as Massachusetts and Connecticut will change their names before they are needed; advantages of giving birth to seven months' babies.
    (Press copy.)
  - Memorandum., 1782 September; A. Mem. 1p.; Appendix
    The British ships "Luxford" and "Will" declared lawful prizes of the "St. James," Capt. Alex[ande]r Cain, "[Lady] Washington," Capt. James Josiah, "Queen of France," Capt. Richard Dale.
  - to Le Ray de Chaumont., Mem. 3p.; Appendix
    Question of M. de Chaumont's account against the United States; most of the doubtful items to be left to M.[Ferdinand] Grand to decide.
  - to [George] Fox., 1783 March; Printed N. 1p.; Appendix. Passy
  - to Sir Joseph Banks., 1783 August 30; A. Dr. of L. 5p.; Appendix. Passy
    Account of balloon experiments in France; M. [Joseph Michel] Montgolfier's invention; pleasantries concerning the future utility of balloons.
  - to Sir Joseph Banks., 1783 October 8; A. Dr. of L. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin
    Sending an account of two balloon ascensions; Messrs. [Jacques Alexandre César] Charles and Robert soon to make important experiments.
  - to Sir Joseph Banks., 1783 November 21; A. Dr. of L. 4p.; Franklin, Benjamin
    Animated account of a balloon ascension which had recently taken place near the residence of the Dauphin; the balloon inflated with hot air produced by burning straw.
  - to Sir Joseph Banks., 1783 December 15; A.L.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin
    Sends him, as President of the Royal Society, M.[Jacques Alexandre César] Charles's account of his balloon ascension.
  - to The Farmers-General., A.L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Advising them to present their accounts to Mr. [Robert] Morris, Superintendent of Finance; suggestion that tobacco be sent to France in part payment.
  - to Count de Salmes., 1785 July 5; A. Dr. of L. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin
    Mentioning other attempts to apply keys to the harmonica; none very successful.
  - to ----- -----., A. Dr. of L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Explaining Mr. Merckle's position with regard to his contracts with Congress. Release of duties, by the Court of France, on these goods.
  - to Madame ----- -----., A. Dr. of L. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Introducing l'Abbé de la Roche, Chaplain to the Comte d'Artois.
  - to ----- -----., A. Mem. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Answers to hypothetical questions regarding a citizen's duty, should the chief of a Civil Society resolve the ruin of a part of that Society.
  - to William Penn., 1705 May 19; A.L.S. 13p.; Lloyd, David. Philadelphia
    Denies the justice and truth of his complaints; accuses him of breaking his promises and of neglecting the rights of the Friends; the Colony's wish that he should remain its Proprietor and that he should continue to furnish a Lieutenant to rule in his stead, but that this Lieutenant should not have power to prorogue or dissolve the Assembly; defends the [Pennsylvania] Assembly against Penn's attacks.
  - to Horace Walpole., 1732; D. 14p.; Logan, Jim, (James)
    A memorial of the state of the British plantations in America; compares them with those of France. Trade with the Indians.
    (Copy by Benjamin Franklin.)
  - to T Jackson., 1740; L. 3p.; Penn, Thomas
    Quarrel between the Governor [George Thomas] and the Assembly; machinations of the Friends. The French threatening to make a settlement within fifty miles of the western boundary. Praises the actions of the Governor.
  - to "Our Friends and Brethren at the Meeting for Sufferings in London.", 1755 May 5; L.S. John Armitt, Sam[ue]l Powel, Thomas Rose, John Reynell, Sam[ue]l Preston Moore, Isr[ael] Pemberton, Antho[ny] Morris, Hugh Roberts. 4p.; The Quarterly Meeting of Friends. Philadelphia
    Accusing the present Proprietors of a disposition to deprive them of Charter privileges; they appear to forget that the first settlers of Pennsylvania were neither criminals nor paupers, but men who came to America for conscience sake. Power of the Friends in the Legislature. The Friends in England asked to have a personal conference with the Proprietors of Pennsylvania; difficulties of the Province recently set forth in an address to the King.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, [1757.]; Printed L. 4p. 2d Edition.; "Obadiah Honesty." A Remonstrance
    Defending Rev. [William] S[mi]th against the charge of evasion or equivocation.
  - to The Author of "The Chronicle.", [1758.]; 1p.; -----,-----
    Poem, entitled "Labour in Vain, or An Attempt to Wash the Black-Moor White." Printed broadside.
    (Illustrated.)
  - to ----- -----., 1762 August 8; L. 1p.; Coyendahi Indian Tribe. Lancaster
    Refusing to grant the white men's petition for a road through their country, because it would mean the driving away of all game, and their own extinction.
  - to The Public., 1764 September 29; 1p.; Galloway, Joseph. Philadelphia
    Defending himself against Mr. John Dickinson's charge of having obtruded on the public a pretended speech.
    Printed broadside.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1764; 1p.; Dove?, David James
    The addition to the epitaph, without the copper-plate. A prayer to Satan. Printed broadside.
    General note
    See C.R. Hildehem, Issues of the Press in Pennsylvania, II, 3, No. 1938.
  - to Philip Syng., 1765 January 17; L.S. 1p.; Penn, John. Philadelphia
    Wish of the Proprietaries that their located, uncultivated lands in Pennsylvania shall not be taxed at any higher rate than any other similar land in the Province.
  - to George Wilkinson, Bladensburg, Md., 1765 August 6; A.L.S. 1p.; Wilkinson, James. London
    Advising him not to return to England until his time is out; his wife and child well.
  - Appendix, 1p.; Six Arguments Against Choosing Joseph Galloway an Assemblyman
    Addressed to himself by one heretofore his friend.
  - to The Public., 1770 June 30; 1p.; William Semple, Alexander Bartram, James Stuart and Robert Wilson. Philadelphia
    Confessing to having violated the non-importation agreement. Printed broadside.
  - to The Inhabitants of Philadelphia., 1770 July 14; 1p.; A Pennsylvanian. Philadelphia
    A vigorous condenmation of New York's desertion of the Colonial cause; urgent appeal to be firm and united. Printed broadside.
  - to The Public., 1770 July 30; 2p.; Towne, Benjamin. Philadelphia
    Detailed account of the trouble between himself and William Goddard, joint owners and publishers of the "Pennsylvania Chronicle." Printed sheet.
  - to The Public., 1770 August 1; 1p.; Goddard, William. Philadelphia
    A most abusive amaignment of his former partners in the "Pennsylvania Chronicle," Joseph Galloway and Thomas Wharton, [Sr.]; begs the public to suspend judgment until he can lay his case before them.
  - to Mrs. [Deborah] Franklin., 1770 September 4; A. Bill.; Hopkinson, Francis. Philadelphia
    Bill for goods bought from him.
    [Written on back of engraved advertisement of Francis Hopkinson, dealer in Cloths and Suitable Trimmings.]
  - to "The Tradesmen, Farmers and Other Inhabitants of Philadelphia.", 1770 September 4; 1p.; A Tradesman. Northern-Liberties Philadelphia
    Appeal to them nor to permit a few men to repeal the non-importation agreement of Pennsylvania. Printed broadside.
  - to [Whom it May Concern]., 1772 November 19; D.S. 1p.; Elizer, Isaac. Newport, R.I
    Certifying to the integrity and ability of Capt. Richard Grinnel, of Newport.
  - to Governor William Franklin., L.S. 1p.; Lewis Johnston and Thirty-one Others
    Petition to the Council and Legislature to forbid the practice of "Physick and Surgery" except by such persons as should pass an examination.
  - to The Freemen, Citizens of Philadelphia, 1773 June 16; 1p.; A Philadelphian
    Warning them against the City Council's arrogation of certain powers not given them by the Charter. Printed broadside.
  - to The Delaware Pilots and Capt. Ayres, 1773 November 27; 1p.; The Committee for Tarring and Feathering. Philadelphia
    Warning the Delaware Pilots not to permit Capt. Ayres, of the ship "Polly," to reach Philadelphia with his cargo of tea from London; warning Capt. Ayres not to land his cargo. Printed broadside.
  - to The Inhabitants of Pennsylvania., 1p.; Civis
    Answer to Publicus who has written in favor of the Excise Law. Printed broadside.
  - to The Public., 1773; 1p.; Civis
    Unjustly reviled by Titus Ironicus and Publicus in a controversy over the Excise; challenges his defamers to make known their identity. Printed broadside.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1774 December 6; 1p.; Jacob Rush, Secretary Pro tem. Committee Chamber, Philadelphia
    Resolves concerning the auction of imported goods. Printed broadside.
  - to ----- D'Esparre., 1775 April 24; L.S. 1p.; de Sartine, Antoine Raymond Jean Gualbert Gabriel. Versailles
    Acknowledging his proposal of the 8th inst. for taking advantage of the present situation of the British Colonies; rejects it however, owing to the good feeling between France and Great Britain.
  - Appendix, 1776 January 5; 1p.; Francis Dashwood, Baron Le Despencer and H.F. Thynne, His Majesty's Postmaster-General. London
    A table of the rates of postage. Printed broadside
  - Appendix, 1776 February 5; 1p.; The Committee of Inspection and Observation of the City of Philadelphia. Philadelphia
    Declaring John Drinker, Thomas and Samuel Fisher enemies to their country and precluded from all trade or intercourse with the inhabitants of these Colonies, owing to their refusal to receive bills of credit emitted by Congress. Peter Z[achary] Lloyd, Sec[retar]y. Printed broadside.
  - Appendix, 1776 December; Memoir. 4p.; Respecting the Hiring of German Troops
  - Appendix, 1777 February 6; D.S. John Hancock, Pres[ident]. 1p.; The Continental Congress, Marine Committee. Philadelphia
    Appointing Robert Robinson on officer on board the sloop "Hornet."
    A.E. This warrant shall serve instead of a commission and authorizes him to act as Lieuteuant under his command. S. Jno. P[aul] Jones. On board the "Bon Homme Richard." 1779 June 10.
  - Appendix, 1777 March 27; D.S. Geo[rge] Germain, Goof[rey] Lee Farrant, Registrar. 12p.; The High Court of Admiralty of England. Court of St. James
    Instructions given to Letter of Marque Ships, commissioned to seize the vessels belonging to the inhabitants of the rebellious Colonies.
    E. " Taken in ye 'Mirtha.' "
  - to [Whom it May Concern]., 1777 March 29; A.L.S. 3p.; Hood, Thomas. Paris
    Deposition, made before Silas Deane, of the unjustifiable treatement meted out to an American prisoner by the English.
    (Attested by Silas Deane.)
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1777 April 1; 2p.; Swift, Richard
    A humorons imitation of a Muster-roll. Printed broadside.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, 1777 April 11, 12; 1p.; The Continental Congess. Philadelphia
    Resolution relative to saving the stores in Philadelphia from being captured by the British. printed broadside.
  - to Silas Deane., 1777 June 29; L. 4p.; Morris, Robert. Philadelphia
    Expressing the greatest indignation at the conduct of the Commissioners in giving public letters to Congress, containing damaging accounts of his brother [Thomas Morris]'s actions as American Agent in France; does not deny the charges but resents the unnecessary publicity given the affair. Report that Dr. Franklin was willing to dismiss Morris in order to make a place for nephew and a partner [Jonathan Williams, Jr.].
  - to Capt. Lawrence, of the Prize snow, "Nancy.", 1777 July 11; L.S. 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Orders concerning the snow's cargo.
  - to ----- Odea., 1777 July 11; L.S. 1p.; Willams, Jonathan Jr. Nantes
    Orders to captains of all prizes to address themselves to the writer.
  - to Augustin Guichard., 1777 July 12; L.S. 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Orders concerning the "Sally's" cargo.
  - Appendix, 1777 July 14; L.S. Artemas Ward, President. 1p.; The State of Massachusetts Bay. Boston
    Appointing William Addiscott master of the Continental schooner "Lee."
  - Appendix, 1777 June 25 to July 30; L. 4p.; The Pennsylvania Journal
    Letters between General Washington and [Gen. Sir William] Howe, concerning the exchange of prisoners; capture of Major-General [Richard] Prescott; question of exchanging him for Gen. [Charles] Lee.
  - to [The People of Pennsylvania, Delaware and Maryland]., 1777 August 27; 1p.; Howe, Sir William. Headquarters of the British Army
    Declaration. Promising amnesty to all who should return to their allegiance. Printed broadside.
  - to The President and Council of Pennsylvania., 1777 September 4; Printed L. 1p.; Israel Pembertor, John Hunt and Samuel Pleasants. Philadelphia
    A remonstrance against their unjust imprisonment.
  - to The Congress., 1777 September 5; 1p.; Israel Pemberton, James Pemberton, John Pemberton, Thomas Wharton Sr., Henry Drinker, Thomas Fisher, Samuel Pleasants and Samuel R. Fisher. Philadelphia
    Protesting against being sent to prison without a trial. Printed Broadside.
  - to [Pierre] Landais., 1777 September 18; L.S. 3p.; Montieu and de Francy. Marseilles
    Concerning the cargo of the "Flamand"; orders to receive no army officers on board.
  - to [Jonathan] Williams, [Jr]., 1777 October 21; Mem. 1p.; Mercier, -----. Nantes
    Expenses incurred for arms and repairs paid from money of the United States entrusted to him by [Jonathan] Williams, [Jr.].
  - Miscellaneous Letters, [1777.]; The Number of Foreign Troops Engaged by Great Britain for the Campaign of 1777 in America
    As agreed to in the treaty, signed December 11, 1776.
  - to His Friend in Dominica., L.S. 3p.; An Officer in New York
    Concerning the trouble between the British and Hessian troops.
  - Miscellaneous Letters, [1777.]; 1p.; Memorandum
    Minutes of the last despatch; battle between Generals Howe and Washington; treachery on the part of the Quakers; Howe's entry into Philadelphia.